Guide to the University Senate Library Committee Records 1945-1979
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
University Senate Library Committee Records
1945-1979
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Archives 71
Washington State University. University Senate Library Committee.
1 Linear foot of shelf space 1 box
The ten bound volumes contain minutes of the committee meetings, correspondence reports, statistical records, memoranda, and other communications received and transmitted by the Washington State University Senate Library Committee.
The Library Committee of the University Senate was formed to function as liaison between the faculty, students, and the University administration; to study library services and policies including budget matters; and to make appropriate recommendations to the University Senate. Furthermore, the Committee acts at the request of the Senate, the administration, or the Director of Libraries in helping to solve special problems related to the library. The Committee is composed of eight faculty members from the various areas in the University (one being a non-administrative faculty member with the rank of Librarian) serving three-year terms, three students (one of whom is a graduate student) serving two-year terms, and the Director of Libraries (ex-officio). The chairperson is to be elected by the Committee. The Committee is responsible to the University Senate and reports to both the University Senate and the Academic Vice-President and Provost. Prior to the organization of the University Senate in 1971 the committee was a presidential committee called the Library Advisory Committee.
The ten bound volumes contain minutes of the committee meetings, correspondence reports, statistical records, memoranda, and other communications received and transmitted by the Committee. There are records of discussions pertaining to the building and subsequent remodeling of Holland Library, library procedures and policies, and rulings from the administration on various issues relating to the Washington State University Library.
There are no records for the years 1972-1975 when the University's committee structure was being reorganized under the University Senate. The last folder briefly covers the years 1976-1979.
The collection is arranged in a single chronological series from 1945 to 1979. The first ten folders include bound volumes which contain all the records from the Committee from 1945-1971. These volumes usually contain two years of records, however some contain more. These bound volumes have been considered as one item. The eleventh folder contains some loose materials from the years 1976 to 1979.
This collection is open and available for research use.
The records of the University Senate Library Committee were transferred to the University Archives, Washington State University, in August 1979 (UA 79-21).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington State University. University Senate Library Committee -- Records and correspondence.; Washington State University. Libraries -- History -- Archives.; Washington State University. Libraries -- Administration -- Archives.; State College of Washington. Library Advisory Committee.
Academic libraries -- Washington (State) -- Pullman -- Administration -- Archives.
Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
- 1945-1947, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1947-1949, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1949-1951, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1951-1953, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1953-1957, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1957-1961, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 1961-1967, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 1967-1969, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 1969-1971, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
- 1976-1979, 50 items (Box 1, Folder 11)